<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: design | Deuleyville]]></title>
  <link href="http://mocha.github.io/blog/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mocha.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-28T05:17:16-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mocha.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Patrick Deuley]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[User Input]]></title>
    <link href="http://mocha.github.io/blog/2013/07/28/user-input/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-28T05:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mocha.github.io/blog/2013/07/28/user-input</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m working on an interesting project right now where I&rsquo;m re-designing a tool that a lot of people in my company use. It&rsquo;s a very old tool, and it&rsquo;s been touched by thousands of people over the years, on a daily basis in most cases. As one usually does when going in to a re-design project, I&rsquo;m asking people who have a vested interest in the final outcome to tell me what they would like to see change. This is usally an extremely helpful place to start&hellip;</p>

<p>But lately, when talking to my users for this project, I&rsquo;ve observed an interesting phenomenon on many occasions: Asking for user input is useless when the user can&rsquo;t comprehend the design changing.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s been such a history around this project that no one actually thinks it will change, and until you can break that barrier in their mind, they can&rsquo;t conceptualize anything changing. You can get them to outline small, iterative changes &ndash; but nothing structurally different.</p>

<p>&ldquo;What <em>else</em> would you like to see on this page? Is there any information left out?&rdquo; is met with blank stares. Asking them instead, &ldquo;What if I added _____ to the page, would that help?&rdquo; might be met with agreement. However, the user can&rsquo;t seem to get there themselves, even though they use this software every day, and really ought to have suggestions for improvement.</p>

<p>How often does this happen to us in our daily lives? We complain about how something is broken and how someone can fix it, but we tend to build bridges over and around these problems instinctually in any case. Once those bridges have been in place long enough, we start to forget they&rsquo;re there &ndash; it&rsquo;s as if they were part of the landscape in the first place.</p>

<p>So what is the best way to get around this problem?</p>

<p>So far, I&rsquo;ve been trying to familiarize myself as much as possible with my user workflow patterns, learning how they use the product as deeply as I can before I say a single word. This is always a great approach to things, however when you can coax out good user input, it&rsquo;s not always entirely necessary.</p>

<p>From there I&rsquo;ve been building a list of ways that I, as a brand new user, see improvements. I&rsquo;ll take that list and propose it to real users, and while most of it gets thrown out, what sticks is something novel that they couldn&rsquo;t have come up with on their own (most of the time, at least.)</p>

<p>All of this aside, this worries me. How many problems are there out there could we fix immediately if we could only just train ourselves to recognize them again? I feel like there are so many micro-complaints I have daily that I&rsquo;m just passing over because I&rsquo;ve gotten so used to having them. Would my life improve if I actually took the time to fix these things?</p>

<p>Maybe I need someone to come follow me around find out for me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
